Never turn your back on the past.
Seraphim Falls is a western, action, drama film directed by David Von Ancken.
The Civil War has ended, but Colonel Morsman Carver is on one final
mission – to kill Gideon, no matter what it takes.
Launched by a gunshot and propelled by rage, the relentless pursuit takes the two men through frigid snow-capped mountains and
arid deserts, far from the comforts and codes of civilisation, into the bloodiest recesses of their own souls.
Carver, played by Liam Neeson.
Gideon, played by Pierce Brosnan.
Hayes, played by Michael Wincott.
Railroad Foreman, played by Xander Berkeley.
Parsons, played by Ed Lauter.
Henry, played by Kevin J. O'Connor.
Seraphim Falls is a 2006 American revisionist Western film directed by television
producer and director David Von Ancken in his only feature film.
The storyline was conceived from a screenplay written
by Von Ancken and Abby Everett Jaques.
The fictional story focuses on a bounty hunt for a Union soldier by a
Confederate colonel following the American Civil War in the late 1860s.
Pierce Brosnan, Liam Neeson, Michael Wincott, Tom Noonan,
and Ed Lauter star in principal roles.
Seraphim Falls explores civil topics, such as violence, human survival and war.
The film was produced by the motion picture studio of Icon Productions.
It was commercially distributed by Samuel Goldwyn Films and Destination Films
theatrically, and by Sony Pictures Home Entertainment for home media.
The film score was composed by musician Harry Gregson-Williams, although a
soundtrack version for the motion picture was not released to the public.
Seraphim Falls premiered at the 2006 Toronto International Film Festival and was released to theatres in limited
release in the United States on January 26, 2007, grossing $418,296 in domestic ticket sales.
It earned an additional $801,762 in box office business overseas for
a combined worldwide total of $1,220,058 in revenue.
The film generally received positive critical reviews
before its initial screening in cinemas.
Notable similarities have been found between the film and the 1976 revisionist
western, The Outlaw Josey Wales directed by Clint Eastwood.
The film explores themes of colonel, frontier, stalking, storm, remedy.
The tone is emotional.